{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"51622912","name":"Anchor Bar ","address":"450 W Fort St","zipcode":"48226","owner":"The Elia Group","licenseNumber":"238103","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"180","coords":"-83.05182,42.32916","geojson":{"id":"51622912","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.051822439,42.329163664]},"properties":{"name":"Anchor Bar ","owner":"The Elia Group","address":"450 W Fort St","zipcode":"48226","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":"High","license_number":"238103","establishmentid":"51622912","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Open","review_frequency_days":"180","most_recent_license_date":"5/1/2019"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"1597","name":"Anchor Bar","address":"450 W Fort St","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"51622993","name":"Continental-Comerica 411","address":"411 West Lafayette Ave ","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"3867","name":"Sterling Services Comerica 411","address":"411 W Lafayette Ave","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"3992","name":"Motor City Kitchen Market","address":"525 W Lafayette St","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"3956","name":"Motor City Kitchen","address":"525 W Lafayette Blvd","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"240","name":"The Detroit Club ","address":"712 Cass Ave","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"1387","name":"Cobo Joe's","address":"422 W Congress","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"51622569","name":"Elephant Room","address":"439 Congress St","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"5388","name":"The Drink Hall","address":"408 W Congress","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4124","name":"Gateway Deli","address":"333 W Fort St","zipcode":"48226"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"51068","inspectionDate":"2020-03-10T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-101.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be safe, unADULTERATED and honestly presented. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2020-03-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"5-202.12","violationDescription":"(A) A handwashing sink shall be equipped to provide water at a temperature of at least 38°C (100°F) through a mixing valve or combination faucet. (Pf)  \r\n(B) A steam mixing valve may not be used at a handwashing sink.  \r\n(C) A self-closing, slow-closing, or metering faucet shall provide a flow of water for at least 15 seconds without the need to reactivate the faucet.   \r\n(D) An automatic handwashing facility shall be installed in accordance with manufacturer's instructions.\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-703.11","violationDescription":"After being cleaned, EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be SANITIZED  by an approved process.\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"5-402.11","violationDescription":"Except as otherwise allowed, a direct connection may not exist between the SEWAGE system and a drain originating from EQUIPMENT in which FOOD, portable EQUIPMENT, or UTENSILS are placed. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"2-301.14","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall clean their hands and exposed portions of their arms as specified under § 2-301.12 immediately before engaging in FOOD preparation including working with exposed FOOD, clean EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES (P) and:\r\n(A)     After touching bare human body parts other than clean hands and clean, exposed portions of arms; (P)\r\n(B)     After using the toilet room; (P)\r\n(C)     After caring for or handling SERVICE ANIMALS or aquatic animals as specified in ¶ 2-403.11(B); (P).\r\n(D)     Except as specified in ¶ 2-401.11(B), after coughing, sneezing, using a handkerchief or disposable tissue, using tobacco, eating, or drinking; (P)\r\n(E)     After handling soiled EQUIPMENT or UTENSILS; (P)\r\n(F)     During FOOD preparation, as often as necessary to remove soil and contamination and to prevent cross contamination when changing tasks; (P)\r\n(G)     When switching between working with raw FOOD and working with READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(H)     Before donning gloves for working with FOOD; (P) and\r\n(I)      After engaging in other activities that contaminate the hands. (P)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2020-03-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-601.11","violationDescription":"(A) EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be clean to sight and touch. (Pf)\r\n(B) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking EQUIPMENT and pans shall be kept free of encrusted grease deposits and other soil accumulations. \r\n(C) NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be kept free of an accumulation of dust, dirt, FOOD residue, and other debris. \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\r\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\r\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-302.15","violationDescription":"Raw fruits and vegetables shall be thoroughly washed to remove soil and other contaminants before being prepared or served. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2020-03-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-301.14","violationDescription":"A sign or poster that notifies FOOD EMPLOYEES to wash their hands shall be provided at all HANDWASHING SINKS used by FOOD EMPLOYEES and shall be clearly visible to FOOD EMPLOYEES.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"2-402.11","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall wear hair restraints such as hats, hair coverings or nets, beard restraints, and clothing that covers body hair, that are designed and worn to effectively keep their hair from contacting exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; or unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE or SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2020-03-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"48650","inspectionDate":"2019-08-06T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"7-201.11","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL shall be stored so they can not contaminate FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES by:   \r\n(A) Separating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL by spacing or partitioning; (P) and   \r\n(B) Locating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL in an area that is not above FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.  This paragraph does not apply to EQUIPMENT and UTENSIL cleaners and sanitizers that are stored in WAREWASHING areas for availability and convenience if the materials are stored to prevent contamination of FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES. (P)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/with","subProblem":"Food","location":"BAR","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-08-06T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-304.15","violationDescription":"(A) SINGLE-USE gloves shall be used for one task only and discarded when      damaged, soiled, or when interruptions occur in the operation. (P)\r\n\r\n(B) Slash-resistant and cloth gloves shall be used in direct contact only with FOOD that is subsequently cooked. Gloves used with ready-to-eat foods shall be smooth,   durable and non-absorbant.\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Single-use glove(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Used for multiple purposes","subProblem":"","location":"COOK LINE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-08-06T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-304.15","violationDescription":"(A) SINGLE-USE gloves shall be used for one task only and discarded when      damaged, soiled, or when interruptions occur in the operation. (P)\r\n\r\n(B) Slash-resistant and cloth gloves shall be used in direct contact only with FOOD that is subsequently cooked. Gloves used with ready-to-eat foods shall be smooth,   durable and non-absorbant.\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"COOK LINE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-08-06T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\r\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\r\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \r\n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\r\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"disposable, paper towels","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-08-19T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-302.12","violationDescription":"Except for containers holding FOOD that can be readily and unmistakably recognized such as dry pasta, working containers holding FOOD or FOOD ingredients that are removed from their original packages for use in the FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, such as cooking oils, flour, herbs, potato flakes, salt, spices, and sugar shall be identified with the common name of the FOOD.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not identified","subProblem":"","location":"DRY STORAGE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-202.15","violationDescription":"Outer openings of a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT shall be protected against the entry of insects and rodents. Unless otherwise allowed by law. \r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Outer opening(s)","subItem":"door(s)","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"DINING AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"2-401.11","violationDescription":"(A)    An EMPLOYEE shall eat, drink, or use any form of tobacco only in designated areas where the contamination of exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES; or other items needing protection can not result.\r\n(B)     A FOOD EMPLOYEE may drink from a closed BEVERAGE container if the container is handled to prevent contamination of:\r\n         (1)     The EMPLOYEE'S hands;\r\n         (2)     The container; and\r\n         (3)     Exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Beverage container","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored improperly","subProblem":"With exposed food","location":"PREP AREA(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"44790","inspectionDate":"2019-01-04T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-601.11","violationDescription":"(A) EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be clean to sight and touch. (Pf)\r\n(B) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking EQUIPMENT and pans shall be kept free of encrusted grease deposits and other soil accumulations. \r\n(C) NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be kept free of an accumulation of dust, dirt, FOOD residue, and other debris. \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s)","subItem":"Equipment","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"EMPLOYEE (LOCKER AREA)","subLocation":"Near the Three compartment sink","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean prior to opening"},{"violationCode":"6-301.11","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of 2 adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with a supply of hand cleaning liquid, powder, or bar soap. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Soap","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"ICE MACHINE","subLocation":"Near the Three compartment sink","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"A designated dressing room/area shall be provided and used."},{"violationCode":"2-102.11","violationDescription":"The PERSON IN CHARGE shall demonstrate this knowledge by compliance with this Code, by being a certified FOOD protection manager who has shown proficiency of required information through passing a test that is part of an ACCREDITED PROGRAM, or by responding correctly to the inspector's questions as they relate to the specific FOOD operation. (Pf)","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not ensuring compliance","subProblem":"","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"Throughout Facility","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-01-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Knowledge is to be obtained through an approved training program"},{"violationCode":"8-304.11","violationDescription":"Upon acceptance of the PERMIT issued by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY, the PERMIT HOLDER in order to retain the PERMIT shall:\r\n(A) Post the PERMIT in a location in the FOOD ESTABLISHMENT that is conspicuous to CONSUMERS; \r\n(B) Comply with the provisions of this Code including the conditions of a granted VARIANCE as specified under § 8-103.12, and APPROVED plans as specified under § 8-201.12;\r\n(C) If a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT is required under § 8-201.13 to operate under a HACCP PLAN, comply with the plan as specified under § 8-103.12;\r\n(D) Immediately contact the REGULATORY AUTHORITY to report an illness of a FOOD EMPLOYEE or CONDITIONAL EMPLOYEE as specified under ¶ 2-201.11(B); \r\n(E) Immediately discontinue operations and notify the REGULATORY AUTHORITY if an IMMINENT HEALTH HAZARD may exist as specified under § 8-404.11;\r\n(F) Allow representatives of the REGULATORY AUTHORITY access to the FOOD ESTABLISHMENT as specified under § 8-402.11;\r\n(G) Except as specified under ¶ (H) of this section, replace existing facilities and EQUIPMENT specified in § 8-101.10 with facilities and EQUIPMENT that comply with this Code if:\r\n(1) The REGULATORY AUTHORITY directs the replacement because the facilities and EQUIPMENT constitute a public health HAZARD or nuisance or no longer comply with the criteria upon which the facilities and EQUIPMENT were accepted,\r\n(2) The REGULATORY AUTHORITY directs the replacement of the facilities and EQUIPMENT because of a change of ownership, or\r\n(3) The facilities and EQUIPMENT are replaced in the normal course of operation;\r\n(H) Upgrade or replace refrigeration EQUIPMENT as specified under Subparagraph 3-501.16(A)(2)(b), if the circumstances specified under Subparagraphs (G)(1) - (3) of this section do not occur first, and 5 years pass after the REGULATORY AUTHORITY adopts this Code;\r\n(I) Comply with directives of the REGULATORY AUTHORITY including time frames for corrective actions specified in inspection reports, notices, orders, warnings, and other directives issued by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY in regard to the PERMIT HOLDER'S FOOD ESTABLISHMENT or in response to community emergencies; \r\n(J) Accept notices issued and served by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY according to LAW; and \r\n(K) Be subject to the administrative, civil, injunctive, and criminal remedies authorized in LAW for failure to comply with this Code or a directive of the REGULATORY AUTHORITY, including time frames for corrective actions specified in inspection reports, notices, orders, warnings, and other directives.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"Throughout Facility","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Person-in-charge must ensure compliance with items listed above."}]}]}],"maxInspectionDate":[{"inspectionDate":"2020-10-30T00:00:00"}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"51622912"}}